eticketing.co.uk 2012-09-19

# Ticketmaster - Legal Guide

### About Ticketmaster and this Privacy Policy

Ticketmaster UK Limited ("Ticketmaster") is a company registered in England (company number 02662632) and a data controller registered with the Information Commissioner's Office (registration number Z5992616). Please read this privacy policy carefully, as it describes what personal information we collect and obtain and how we use it.

### The Information We Collect When You Use the Website

When you browse this website ("Site"), information about your visit is automatically stored in our web server logs. The server logs stores the details of the pages and content you request when you click on the links in our website. For example, it will store your IP address and the date and time of page requests.

We also collect information about your website usage using cookies. For more information about the cookies on this Site and how to disable cookies, please read the Ticketmaster Cookie Policy.

You can browse our Site without providing us any personal information, but to purchase tickets, you must create a [MyTicketmaster account](https://www.ticketmaster.ie/member?tm_link=tm_homeA_ql_1). Once you register with Ticketmaster some of the information we collect about your use of this Site will be linked to your [MyTicketmaster account](https://www.ticketmaster.ie/member?tm_link=tm_homeA_ql_1).

### Information We Request Directly From You

We collect various personal details when you fill in our registration and order forms (like your name, phone numbers, address, email address etc). We also keep a record of your transactions with Ticketmaster and any correspondence between us.

You may be asked for further information if we run surveys, competitions, prize draws and other promotional activities. If this is the case, then this Privacy Policy will apply to the personal information you provide, but please check for any specific terms that apply each time you participate in these activities.

If you'd prefer not to give us any personal information when you purchase tickets for events, then please visit the Box Office at the venue where an event is taking place.

The financial information we collect and how we use it is explained later in this Privacy Policy.

### Information Which We Obtain

We may also add information to your details, which we have obtained from other companies or sources. For example, we may cross check the accuracy of the information we hold with other databases, or we may add demographic information. Much of this data is created using publicly available sources such as the edited electoral register or the Postal Address File, or is derived from market research such as consumer panel surveys. 

### How We Use Personal Information

**Our Event Partners**

As an authorised ticket agent, Ticketmaster sells tickets on behalf the providers of the live events for which you buy tickets. This might be an artist, venue, promoter, fan club, sports club or organisation, producer or sponsor. We refer to the organisers or providers of an event as our "Event Partners". When you purchase tickets for an event, we share your personal information with our Event Partner, but only if you have bought tickets for the events that they are providing. There may be more than one Event Partner for each event.

Ticketmaster is data controller in respect of all of the information which Ticketmaster collects and receives about you when you use our services. The Event Partner (in common with Ticketmaster) is a data controller of the information which relates to their events.

### Providing, Improving and Customising Our Services

We use your information primarily to provide you with the services and products you request, and related customer services (this includes providing this Site, website administration and security).

We also analyse this information to improve our understanding of you and our customer base in general. We do this so that we can make better decisions about our services, advertising, products and content, based on a more informed picture of how our customers use our current services, and to provide you with a more customised experience.

Depending on your marketing preferences, we may use this information to help us to determine which offers, information, discounts and promotions you would most like to receive.

**Direct Marketing**

When you first register with the Site, you can decide whether your contact information may be used by us, our Event Partners and selected third parties for direct marketing purposes. Depending on your selection, Ticketmaster, its group companies, Event Partners and/or other third parties may contact you by e-mail or post with information or offers regarding their goods and services such as discounts, exclusive offers or special event information.

Unless you opt-out, Ticketmaster will send you a weekly TicketAlert with information about upcoming shows and events. If you purchase a ticket for an event, your address will be entered into Ticketmaster's PerformerAlert service. This service sends you e-mail updates when the same artist, event or festival announces new dates in the future.

You will be given an opportunity to unsubscribe in every marketing e-mail we send you.

**Changing your Marketing Preferences**

If you change your mind or want to amend your marketing preferences, you can do so at any time from your [MyTicketmaster](https://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/member/edit_subscriptions?tm_link=mytm_SignIn) account.

Sign up: new events often sell out fast, so a [MyTicketmaster](https://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/member/edit_subscriptions?tm_link=mytm_SignIn) account lets you set up alerts for your favourite artists, festivals, bands, teams, venues and other events to make sure you never miss out on an opportunity to buy tickets when they go on sale through Ticketmaster. Click here for more information about Ticketmaster's TicketAlerts, PerformerAlerts and VenueAlerts and to sign up.

Opt-out: You may opt out of any of Ticketmaster's marketing communications at any time. If you wish to unsubscribe now, please click the following link, insert your email address into the link as indicated and click the "Go" button or arrow in your web browser:

<https://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/member/unsubscribe?email_address=InsertEmailAddressHere>

Please note that our systems may take a little time to fully register your updates, so if you continue to receive emails in the 48 hours after making changes, please accept our apologies and ignore them.

Please also note that you will always continue to receive customer service emails from Ticketmaster - these include order confirmations, event reminders, information about changes to an event you've purchased tickets for and reminders to print your TicketFast tickets if you've selected that option for ticket delivery.

**Event Partner Marketing**

You may also receive marketing information from the Event Partners for the events for which you have purchased tickets. If you do not wish to receive marketing correspondence from an Event Partner please use the unsubscribe link in their communications or contact them directly to request that your details are removed from their databases.

**Carefully Selected Third Parties**

If you've given your consent when registering for your personal information to be provided to carefully selected third parties (other than Ticketmaster's Event Partners) they may contact you by post, telephone or email with information or offers regarding their goods and services.

### Information Sharing and Transfer

Ticketmaster and its Event Partners will not share your data with any third parties without your consent, except under the following circumstances:

\- if we use a third party supplier to carry out specific business operations (e.g. a mailing house, a courier, or a market research company) but only if we have in place a written agreement protecting your information;

\- if you have purchased other goods or services via our website such as ticket insurance or merchandise, in which case your information may be shared with third parties to process and fulfil your orders. Please see further information below in relation to how payment information is shared;

\- if Ticketmaster uses group company facilities in the United States or other countries within the EU to carry out specific business operations (e.g. IT and hosting) but only if an adequate level of protection is in place to protect your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998;

\- if we sell or buy any business or assets, we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer but only where we have taken reasonable steps to ensure the security and confidentiality of your information;

\- in order to enforce or apply our [terms of use](http://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/legal?tm_link=tm_homeA_i_ourpolicy), [purchase policy](http://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/legal/purchase.html) or any other applicable Ticketmaster terms and conditions;

\- if you enter a competition, promotion or a prize draw, and Ticketmaster is not the operator, the information you provide will be shared with the operator of the promotion, competition or prize draw;

\- if we consider it necessary to comply with laws or regulations, to assist law enforcement, to protect the rights, property, or safety of Ticketmaster, our customers, users of this Site, or others;

\- if the data is only being shared in an anonymous and aggregate form; or

\- if Ticketmaster or any of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case your information may be one of the transferred assets.

### Financial Information We Collect and How We Use It

If you are purchasing tickets, you will be asked to provide financial information (your payment card information). You will be given the option to save this information so that you don't have to re-enter it every time you buy tickets. If you select this option, we'll store your financial information for 12 months from the date of your most recent purchase, after which it will be deleted.

Financial information we collect is used to authorise payment and bill you for your purchases through our Site. When you make a purchase on the Site, your consent is given to provide your financial or personal information to those third parties necessary to process your transactions with us, such as credit card companies and banks. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Where we do share this data, we apply payment industry standard encryption methods to maintain its security.

If you've ordered any additional goods or services through our Site such as Ticket Insurance or merchandise for an event, your information may be passed to the providers of such goods or services so they can process your transaction and provide you with the goods or services you've ordered.

Except as explained above, we will not share your financial information with any third parties without your prior consent.

### Advertising on this Site

This Site contains adverts for Ticketmaster services and also third party advertising. We do not share your personal data with our third parties advertisers (except for demographic data on an aggregate basis) but they may collect information about you using their own cookies and other similar technologies.

Ticketmaster and its third party advertisers may use information collected using cookies and other similar technologies to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and to deliver targeted advertising based on your preferences.

For more information about:

### Other Sites/Third Party Vendors and their Privacy Policies

This Site may contain third party content and links to other websites. Ticketmaster is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites or for the privacy policies and practices of other third parties, and so you should be careful to read those websites' privacy policies independently.

### Our Security Precautions

This Site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We use 128 bit industry standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption for your transactions with us. It encrypts all of your personal information, including payment card number, name, and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We do make some changes and adjustments to this privacy policy from time to time, so please check regularly for any updates. Where there's a significant change to this Privacy Policy, we'll always notify you so that you can decide whether to continue using our services.

### Your Rights

You can use your [MyTicketmaster](https://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/member?tm_link=tm_homeA_header_signin) account to edit and view the information about you that you've provided to us. You also have the right to obtain a copy of the personal data we hold about you to correct any inaccuracies in such data. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us via Customer Services or at [insert address]. For some requests we may ask you to provide: proof of identity, further information to enable us to locate the information you have requested, and/or a payment of £10 to cover our costs. Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible and will not take more than 40 days to process.

### Ticketmaster Cookie Policy

**We are in the process of reviewing how cookies are used on this website. Below is some general information about cookies and how to disable them. Ticketmaster's new cookie policy will be available shortly on this page. Thank you for your patience.**

We may store information about you using cookies. A cookie is a small text file that is automatically issued to your computer when you enter our Site and which is stored by the browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies store some basic information that helps us to identify if a user of your computer has visited the Site before and if you have provided us with some personalised information.

Our Site uses cookies to keep track of what you are purchasing. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password (if you have supplied us with one) so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit our Site, and for other purposes, such as informing you that you may have made multiple bookings for specific events on our Site.

We may also display and/or allow third party advertisers to display advertisements on our Site and we and/or such advertisers may also use cookies to record information about your use of the advertisement which you have seen and the types of things you appear interested in. We and/or third party advertisers may serve advertisements that we and/or any third party advertiser believe are most likely to be of interest to you, based on information about your visit to this and other websites (this information is anonymous in that it does not include your name, street address, e-mail address or telephone number). For more information about this type of online behavioural advertising, please visit www.youronlinechoices.com.

You can disable cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent, but if you choose to do so you may not be able to access some areas of the Site and you may find it difficult to purchase tickets. For more information on deleting or controlling cookies we recommend www.AboutCookies.org.
